二十世纪福克斯公司
出 品
布兰迪公司制作
西 格 妮 · 韦 弗
异           形
查尔斯 S·达顿
查尔斯·丹斯
保尔·麦克盖恩
布赖恩·格洛弗
拉尔夫·布朗
丹尼尔·韦布
克里斯托弗·约翰·费尔兹
霍尔特·麦凯莱尼
兰斯·亨利克森
英国 选角导演
美国 选角导演
普丽西拉·约翰
比利·霍普金斯
服 装 设 计
鲍勃·林伍德 与 大卫·佩里
低温舱发生火警
Fire in cryogenic compartment.
艾略特 · 戈登塞尔
配  乐
重覆 低温舱发生火警
Repeat: Fire in cryogenic compartment.
所有人员速到 紧急逃生小艇发射台报到
All personnel report to emergency-escape vehicle launch pad.
视  觉  特  效
理查德 · 埃德伦德
太空飞行将在20秒后开始
Deep-space flight will commence in T minus 20 seconds.
异形3 造型设计
H . R.  吉格
亚历克·吉利斯 与 汤姆·伍德鲁夫,二世
异 形 特 效 指 导
特 效 监 制
乔治 · 吉布斯
剪  辑
特里 · 罗林斯
诺曼·雷诺兹
艺 术 指 导
亚力 · 汤姆森
摄 影 指 导
西格妮 · 韦弗
联合制片人
埃兹拉 · 斯沃德罗
监   制
人 物 原 型 来 源
丹·欧班农 与 罗纳德·舒塞特
故  事
文森特·沃德
剧  本
大卫·吉勒      沃尔特·希尔
拉里 · 费格森
戈登·卡罗尔    大卫·吉勒
制 作 人
与 沃尔特·希尔
大 卫 · 芬 奇
导   演
费欧娜"复仇"161星
外围矿沙提炼厂
双Y染色体-劳改监狱
最高设防监狱
一艘逃生艇坠落
An EEV's come down.
到沙滩去 可能还有其他人
Get down to the beach. There may be others.
快去
Now!
说话
Talk to me.
费欧娜161 C级监狱 - 12037154
报告逃生小艇
2650坠落
一个幸存者
蕾普莉中尉
希克斯下士-死亡
身份不明女性 死亡
约 10 岁
要求最迅速紧急救援
等候回应-狱长安德鲁
致:费欧娜161 C级监狱
通讯卫星通报
维兰德-宇塔尼公司
收到报告
好了 大家集合
All right, let's get it going.
集合了 快点
Keep it together. Come on. Right?
可以了 迪伦先生
Right. Here we go, Mr. Dillon.
主呀 给我们力量来坚守
Give us strength, O Lord, to endure.
我们只是上帝手中 卑微的罪人
We recognize that we are poor sinners in the hands of an angry God.
请以手包围我们 守护我们
Let the circle be unbroken until the day.
- 阿们 - 阿们
- Amen. - Amen.
谢谢各位
Thank you, gentlemen.
这是谣言管制会议 以下是案情
This is Rumor Control. Here are the facts.
你们也知道
As some of you know,
一架337型号紧急逃生艇
a 337 model EEV crash-landed here
在早上六点坠落此地
at 0600 on the morning watch.
上面有一名生还者 两具尸体
There was one survivor, two dead,
以及损毁得 无法维修的生化人
and a droid that was hopelessly smashed beyond repair.
生还者是个女人
The survivor is a woman.
漂亮吗？
Is she pretty?
我想说我已经发誓 要终生禁欲
I just want to say that I've taken a vow of celibacy...
包括对女人在内
that also includes women.
- 我们全都发过誓 - 闭上你的臭嘴
- We've all taken the vow! - Shut your gob, Morse.
我不喜欢公司政策
I do not appreciate company policy,
让她和囚犯及狱卒 混在一起
allowing her to freely intermingle with inmates and the staff.
这位兄弟想说的是 任何外人
Our brother means to say we view the presence of any outsider,
尤其是一个女人
especially a woman,
都会破坏这里 和谐统一的精神
as a violation of the harmony, a potential break in the spiritual unity.
我们知道 大家的想法
We are aware of your feelings in this matter.
我已申请救援小组前来
You will be pleased to know that I have requested a rescue team.
若无阻碍 一周内将到达 然后尽快将她带离此地
Hopefully they will be here inside of a week and evacuate her ASAP.
少来这一套
Don't give us that!
- 她的身体状况如何？ - 伤势不重
- What's her medical status? - She doesn't seem too badly damaged.
目前昏迷中 未能做更精确诊断
She's unconscious. Can't give you a more specific diagnosis.
- 她能活下来吗？ - 我想应该会
- Will she live? - I would think so.
大家都不希望那女人 在救援小组到达前
It's in everybody's interest she doesn't come out of the infirmary
离开医疗室 没人伴随更不可以 对吗？
until the rescue team arrives, and certainly not without an escort, right?
是
Sir.
各位 我们必须坚守 日常生活 不要过度激动
Gentlemen! We should all stick to our set routine and not get unduly agitated.
对吧？好
Correct? All right.
很好 谢谢大家
Thank you, gentlemen.
好了
All right.
他们最好早点到 否则她就死定了
Better get here soon or there ain't gonna be much left.
那是什么？
What's that?
我自己调的鸡尾酒 给你前所未有的感受
Just a little cocktail of my own mix. Sort of an eye-opener.
- 你是医生？ - 我叫克里蒙斯
- You a doctor? - My name is Clemens.
- 这里的医疗主任 - 这里？
- I'm the Chief Medical Officer here. - Here?
复仇161星
Fury 161.
银河系最偏远的劳动监狱 一提起就令我伤心
It's one of Weyland-Yutani's backwater work prisons, it grieves me to say.
别紧张
Do you mind?
这东西是镇静剂
This is basically a stabilizer.
我得剃掉你的头发 这里的头虱很多
I really ought to shave your head. We have a big problem with lice here.
我帮你剪发 你自己剪耻毛
When you feel better I'll give you some clippers for your private parts.
我是怎么来的？
How did I get here?
你乘坐的逃生艇坠毁
You crash-landed in an EEV.
进入大气层前 才脱离你的母船
Separated from your mother ship before you hit our atmosphere.
知道你长眠多久吗？
Any idea how long you were in hypersleep?
你突然苏醒 可能对身体有影响
Coming out the way you did can jolt your system.
- 我会病几个星期 - 没错
- I'll be sick for a couple of weeks. - Indeed.
- 其他人呢？ - 全死了
- Where are the others? - They didn't make it.
- 什么？ - 无一幸存
- What? - They didn't survive.
我要到船上
I have to get to the ship.
- 你现在还不能去 - 给我穿衣服
- You're in no condition for that. - Wanna get me some clothes,
还是你要我这样出去？
or should I go like this?
考虑到本地居民的性情 我建议你穿衣服
Given the nature of our indigenous population, I would suggest clothes.
他们好久没见过女色
None of them has seen a woman in years.
我也一样
Neither have I, for that matter.
这里曾经收容五千名囚犯
This used to be a 5,000-convict facility,
现在却只有25名
but it's been reduced to a custodial staff of 25.
- 为什么？ - 保持火焰不熄
- Why? - To keep the pilot light on.
什么火焰？
Pilot light for what?
封闭式熔炉
Blast furnace!
天然沼气 我们有个铸造厂 蕾普莉中尉
Natural methane. We have a foundry, Lt Ripley.
囚犯打造铅片 围堵有毒废物
The inmates forge lead sheets for toxic waste containment.
你怎么知道我的名字？
How do you know my name?
就写在你短裤背面
It's stenciled on the back of your shorts.
把铁缆松开
Release the cable!
- 尸体在哪里？ - 在殓房
- Where are the bodies? - We have a morgue.
调查小组一个星期后到达
We put them there until the investigative team arrives - in about a week, I think.
- 有一名生化人 - 残缺不全
- There was a droid. - Disconnected.
到处都是碎片 我们把残骸丢到垃圾场
There were bits and pieces everywhere. We put what was left on the rubbish tip.
那名下士 被安全支架刺死
The corporal was impaled by that safety support.
死得不明不白
Never knew what hit him.
那个女孩呢？
And the girl?
她…溺死在低温舱内
She... drowned in her cryo-tube.
我想她没有知觉… 当她死去时
I don't think she was conscious... when it happened.
很抱歉
Sorry.
- 怎么了？ - 她在哪里？
- What's the matter? - Where is she?
在停尸间
In the morgue.
我要看她
I have to see her.
我要看看她的遗体
I have to see what's left of her.
为何你这么坚持？
Is there any particular reason that you're so insistent?
对 我要确定她的死因
Yes. I have to be sure how she died.
对这种事情 实在不必罗唆
I hate to be repetitious about such a sensitive subject,
但她很明显是溺死的
but it is perfectly clear that she drowned.
她是你女儿吗？
Was she your daughter?
不 她不是
No. She wasn't.
让我独处一下 好吗？
Could I have a moment alone, please?
当然可以
Yes, of course.
原谅我
Forgive me.
她在干嘛？
What's she doing?
你没事吧？
OK?
没事
No.
- 我们得验尸 - 什么？
- We have to do an autopsy. - What?
我说过了 我们得查清楚她的死因
I told you. We have to make sure how she died.
我说过 她是溺死的
And I told you... she drowned.
我不敢肯定
I'm not so sure.
我们得看看她的体内
I have to see inside of her.
- 你精神恍惚 - 我有很好的理由
- You're disorientated. - I have a very, very good reason.
那就请你把理由告诉我
Perhaps you'd like to share that reason?
她很可能受到感染
Possible contagion.
哪种感染？
What kind, exactly?
- 霍乱 - 霍乱
- Cholera. - Cholera?
两百年来 一宗霍乱病例都没有
There hasn't been a case of cholera reported for 200 years.
求求你
Please?
一切正常
Everything's in place.
没有感染的迹象 没有疾病的征状
There's no sign of infection. No indication of disease.
胸腔 打开胸腔
Her chest. Open her chest.
小心点
Careful.
肺部
Lungs...
充满液体
flooded with fluid.
所以她是溺死的
Ergo, she drowned.
我不是白痴
Now, since I'm not a complete idiot,
请告诉我 你到底在找什么？
would you like to tell me what we're really looking for?
- 克先生 - 狱长
- Mr. Clemens. - Superintendent.
你还没见过蕾普莉中尉
I don't believe you've met Lieutenant Ripley.
- 这是怎么回事 克先生？ - 是的 长官 怎么了？
- What's going on, Mr. Clemens? - That's right, sir. What's going on?
我很高兴蕾普莉中尉 已经觉得好很多
First, the lieutenant is feeling much better, I'm happy to say.
另外 基於公共卫生 我正在验尸
Second, in the interest of public health, I am performing an autopsy.
- 没有我的同意？ - 我来不及向你请示
- Without my authority. - There didn't seem to be time.
结果一切无碍 没有感染
But it's turned out all right. There's no sign of contagion.
很好 蕾中尉最好 别在囚犯面前走动
Good. But it might be helpful if Ripley didn't parade around in front of the prisoners,
听说她已经这么做过
as I am told she did in the last hour.
她的状况若有变化 你也要让我知道
It might also be helpful if you informed me of any change in her physical status.
- 这要求过分吗？ - 尸体必须火葬
- Or would that be asking too much? - We have to cremate the bodies.
胡扯 我们要保存尸体 直到救援小组到达
Nonsense. We'll keep the bodies on ice till the rescue team arrives.
冷藏保存
On ice.
这会影响公共卫生
There is the public-health issue.
蕾中尉认为目前 仍有传染病存在的可能
The lieutenant feels there is still the possibility of a communicable infection.
- 你不是说没有疾病征状？ - 这孩子看来是溺死的
- You said there was no sign of disease. - It would appear that the child drowned,
不过未经化验 是不可能完全确定的
but without proper laboratory tests it's impossible to be certain.
我认为不该忽视 感染病毒的可能
I would consider it unwise to tolerate even the possibility of an unwelcome virus.
要是霍乱突然蔓延 你一定会面目无光
An outbreak of... cholera would look extremely bad on a report, would it not, sir?
这所监狱的25名囚犯
We've 25 prisoners in this facility.
全都有双Y染色体
All double-Y chromos.
全是小偷、强奸犯、杀人犯 全都是人渣
All thieves, rapists, murderers, child molesters... All scum.
他们信教 并不代表他们很安全
Just because they've taken on religion doesn't make them any less dangerous.
我不干涉他们的信仰
I try not to offend their convictions.
也不想扰乱这里的秩序
I don't want to upset the order.
我不想引发风波
I don't want ripples in the water.
我也不让女人勾起他们的邪念
And I don't want a woman walking around, giving them ideas.
我懂了 为我自身安全着想
I see. For my own personal safety.
一点也没错
Exactly.
我把火葬的事交给你 克先生
I will leave the details of the cremation to you, Mr. Clemens.
他们可以用熔炉 不过十点以前要回牢房
They may use the furnace, but I want everyone back in lockup by 2200 hours.
圣诞节提早到来
Our Christmas has come early.
- 什么意思？ - 有死牛就是好的
- What do you mean? - Any dead oxes are good.
满身跳蚤的臭东西
Smelly bastards all covered in lice.
现在只剩下七只 就算处理完了
There's only seven of the friggin' things left, then we're done with them.
最讨厌冲洗这臭东西
I hate hosin' these bastards down.
每次搞得我浑身是粪
Always get shite all over me boots.
- 对了 法兰克 - 怎么了
- Talking of hosing things down, Frank... - Yeah?
有机会的话 你想跟她说什么？
If you had the chance, what would you say to her?
- 什么意思？ - 你知道的 有机会的话
- What do you mean? - You know, if you got the chance.
- 你是说平常的时候吗？ - 对
- You mean, casual, like? - Yeah.
要是在饭堂遇到 你会说什么？
How would you put it to her if you bumped into her in the mess hall?
没问题
No problem.
我对女人很有办法
I've never had any problem with the ladies.
我会说"午安 亲爱的 好吗？"
I'd say "Good day, my dear. How's it going?"
"我可以帮你做什么吗？"
"Anything I can do to be of service?"
然后看着她 从上看到下
Then I'd give her the look, up and down.
然后眨眼睛 色迷迷的笑
Then I'd give her the wink. A dirty smile.
- 她就会明白 - 是的
- She'd soon get the picture. - Yeah, right.
她就会说 “来亲我吧 老色鬼”
Then she'd say "Kiss my arse, you horny old bugger."
我会去亲她 浑身上下
I'd be happy to kiss her arse. I'd be happy to kiss her anywhere she wants.
对 但要粗暴点 激烈点 明白吗？法兰克
Yeah, but treat 'em mean, keep 'em keen. Right, Frank?
告诉你 把女王当妓女 把妓女当是女王
Told you before, Murph. Treat a queen like a whore and a whore like a queen.
不会错的
You can't go wrong.
那女孩是怎么死的？
What do you think killed Babe?
不知道 反正已归西
Beats me. She just keeled over.
- 她多大？ - 11岁吧 正值青春
- How old was she? - Guards say 11. In her prime.
算了 等一下切碎了 一样要丢进炉里
Never mind. We'll chop her up later and throw her in the stew.
对
Fine.
法兰克
Hey, Frank.
那是什么？
What's this?
这孩子和这男人 已离开我们的世界
We commit this child and this man to your keeping, O Lord.
他们已远离黑暗
Their bodies have been taken from the shadow of our nights.
他们获得解脱
They have been released
远离黑暗与痛苦
from all darkness and pain.
这孩子和这男人
The child and the man
已离开我们的世界
have gone beyond our world.
他们已达到永恒
They are forever eternal
永垂不朽
and everlasting.
尘归尘
Ashes to ashes,
土归土
dust to dust.
为什么？
Why?
为什么无辜者受到惩罚？
Why are the innocent punished?
为什么必须牺牲？
Why the sacrifice?
为什么有痛苦？
Why the pain?
世间原无承诺
There aren't any promises.
世事无常
Nothing's certain.
少数人能蒙主宠召 得到拯救
Only that some get called, some get saved.
她不会了解我们留在人世 必须面对的困苦和伤痛
She won't ever know the hardship and grief for those of us left behind.
我们将遗体交托于虚无
We commit these bodies to the void...
并且满心欢喜
with a glad heart.
因为每一颗种子 必将长出花朵
For within each seed, there is a promise of a flower.
每次死亡 无论多么微不足道
And within each death, no matter how small,
总有一个新生命
there's always a new life.
一个新的开始
A new beginning.
阿们
Amen.
真奇怪 唯一生还者是女人
I tell ya, it's fuckin' weird. The only one that survived that crash is a woman.
好了
OK.
很多谣言说这里不很和谐
There's a lot of talk going around that we've got some disharmony here.
可以告诉我是什么问题吗？
Any of you guys wanna tell me what the problem is?
告诉我 兄弟
Come on. Speak to me, brothers.
我告诉你
All right, I'll tell you.
我不怕黑暗和虫子
I don't mind the dark. I don't mind the bugs.
也不怕每周一次 走进又湿又冷的隧道中
I don't mind wandering around in some cold, wet, damp tunnel for a week at a time.
但我讨厌葛立
But I mind Golic.
- 是这样吗？ - 对 他又臭又疯疯癫癫
- That the way you feel about it? - Yeah. The guy's crazy and he smells bad.
我不要再和他一起出去
I ain't going out with him any more.
你有什么话要说？
You got anything to say for yourself?
他还是得跟着你们
The boy's going with you.
葛立只是个可怜的废人 和你我没有不同
Golic is just another poor, miserable, suffering son of a bitch, just like you and me.
- 他很臭 - 还疯疯癫癫
- He smells worse. - And he's crazy.
少跟我来这套
Knock off the shit!
你们有事要做
You've got a job to do.
我不要再听到 任何有关葛立的事
I don't wanna hear another word about Golic.
知道吗？
OK?
亚伦先生 如我所想
As I thought, Mr. Aaron.
- 如你所想 - 你作主吧 长官
- As I thought. - You called it, sir.
我只想 谢谢你在葬体说的话
I just wanted to... say thanks for what you said at the funeral.
- 我的朋友一定会很感激… - 你不会想认识我 小姐
- My friends would've appreciated... - You don't wanna know me, lady.
我是专杀女人的强奸犯
I'm a murderer and rapist of women.
真的？
Really?
我猜我一定令你很紧张
I guess I must make you nervous.
- 你有任何信仰吗 妹子？ - 谈不上
- Do you have any faith, sister? - Not much.
这里有很足够的信仰
We've got a lot of faith here.
甚至足够让你加入
Enough even for you.
- 我以为女人不准加入 - 以前从未有过女人
- I thought women weren't allowed. - Well, we've never had any before.
不过我们容忍任何人 甚至令人无法容忍的人
But we tolerate anybody. Even the intolerable.
谢谢
Thank you.
这只是原则 不是针对你
That's just a statement of principle, nothing personal.
在这里等待最好
You see, we've got a good place to wait here.
直到现在…没有任何诱惑
And until now... no temptation.
你们在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
等上帝回来
We're waiting for God to return
救赎我们
and raise his servants to redemption.
五年前迪伦和其他人
Dillon and the rest of the alternative people
接受宗教信仰
embraced religion, as it were, about five years ago.
再喝一杯
Tincture?
- 我正在服药 - 不见得吧
- I'm on medication. - Hardly.
- 哪一种宗教？ - 某种相信千年末世的
- What kind of religion? - Some sort of apocalyptic,
基督教原教旨主义派
millenarian, Christian fundamentalist...
- 对 - 正是
- Right. - Exactly.
问题是公司想关闭监狱
When the company wanted to close the facility down,
迪伦和其他人希望留下
Dillon and the rest of the converts wanted to stay.
他们获准以守卫身份留下
And they were allowed to remain as custodians,
加上两名管理员和 一名医疗主任
with two minders and a medical officer.
就是我们
And here we are.
你怎么得到这么好的差事？
How did you get this wonderful assignment?
你喜欢这新发型吗？
How do you like your new haircut?
还算好
It's OK.
我为了你 得罪安德鲁
Now that I've gone out on a limb for you with Andrews,
我和那好人的关系 现在更加恶化
damaged my already less-than-perfect relationship with that good man,
我也向你说过 复仇161星的无聊历史
and briefed you on the humdrum history of Fury 161,
可否告诉我 在女孩体内找什么？
can you not tell me what you were looking for in the girl?
觉得我有吸引力吗？
Are you attracted to me?
哪一方面？
In what way?
“那”方面
In that way.
你很直接
You're very direct.
我流浪了很久
I've been out here a long time.
我也是
So have I.
∮  In the year 7510
∮  If God's a-comin'
∮  He oughta make it by then
∮  Maybe he'll look around and say
∮  Guess it's time for the Judgment...
∮  In the year
嘿 史派克
Hey, Spike.
你在下面吗？在做什么？
Are you down there? What are you doing?
蒙你垂青我真的很感激
I really appreciate your affections.
但我注意到 你回避我的问题
But I am aware that they deflected my question.
当然你用的方法很巧妙
In the nicest possible way, of course.
你真扫兴
You're spoiling the mood.
我得尽我的职责 我只想知道为何要火葬
I have a job to do. I just want to know why we had to cremate the bodies.
你认为既然上了你的床 就应该回答你
And now that I'm in your cot, you think I owe you an answer.
你得给我一个理由 但这与上不上床无关
I think you owe me an answer. Being in my bed's got nothing to do with it.
我在长眠期间发了可怕的梦 我得知道是什么害死她
I had a terrible dream in hypersleep, and I had to be sure what killed her.
我可能错了
Anyway, I made a mistake.
有可能
Possibly.
现在我又犯了错
And now I've made another mistake.
- 真的？什么错？ - 和囚犯搞关系
- Really? What's that? - Fraternizing with a prisoner.
肉体接触 这触犯规律 对吧？
Physical contact. It's against the rules, isn't it?
当然
Definitely.
- 几时发生的？ - 你应该很清楚
- When was this? - I think you know.
我不是囚犯
I'm not a prisoner.
你脑后有一个电脑条码
You have a bar code on the back of your head.
那的确应该解释
That does deserve an explanation.
不过现在还未到时候
But I don't think now is the moment.
对不起 我令你觉得扫兴
Sorry. We are rather spoiling things, aren't we?
克先生
Mr. Clemens.
亚伦先生
Mr. Aaron.
狱长安德鲁 要你马上到22号通风孔
Superintendent Andrews would like you to report to vent shaft 22. Now.
- 发生了意外 - 严重吗？
- We've had an accident. - Something serious?
可以这么说 有一名囚犯…被切碎了
You could call it that. One of our prisoners has been... diced.
抱歉 得走了
Sorry. I have to go.
有职务在身
Official duties.
- 墨菲 - 你怎么知道
- Murphy. - How do you know?
那是他的靴子
That's his boot.
是我派他来的 他是个笨蛋
I gave him the assignment, sir. He was a wanker.
别自责 亚伦先生 不是你的错
No apologies, Mr. Aaron. It wasn't your fault.
没什么好说的 他当场死亡
Well, not much to say, is there? Death was instantaneous.
可不是
No shit.
我猜他被吸入风扇
I take it he was pulled into the fan.
- 突然而来的一阵风 - 对 我也差点被卷进风扇
- Rush of air, I'd imagine. Except... - Right! Almost happened to me once.
我说过多少次离风扇远点
I've told them so many times: Stay away from the fans.
- 没有人肯听 - 除了风扇一直吹着
- Nobody bloody listens. - Except the fan was blowing.
- 那是什么？ - 不知道
- What's that? - I don't know.
半小时后来见我 克先生
I want to see you in my quarters in 30 minutes, if you please, Mr. Clemens.
你在这儿
Here you are.
你一个人到处乱走 会气死安德鲁
Wandering around without an escort will really piss Superintendent Andrews off.
- 那件意外是怎么回事？ - 一名囚犯死了
- Tell me about your accident. - One of the prisoners has been killed.
真的？怎么死的？
Really? How?
在通风孔
In the air shaft.
可怜的家伙 掉进9尺长的风扇
Poor sod backed into a nine-foot fan.
我在离现场不远 发现一样东西
I found something at the accident site. Just a bit away from where it happened.
一个印痕 烧过的痕迹
A mark. A burn.
就像你在那女孩的低温舱 所发现的
Like the one you found on the girl's cryo-tube.
听着 我跟你同一阵线
Look, I'm on your side.
我想帮你 但我要知道这是怎么回事
I want to help, but I need to know what's going on.
或是 你认为这是怎么回事
Or what you think is going on.
若你想帮我 就找一部语音电脑
If you really wanna help, find me a computer with audio capabilities
让我解读航行记录器
so I can access this flight recorder.
这里没有那种设备
We don't have anything like that here.
- 主教呢？ - 主教？
- What about Bishop? - Bishop?
跟我一起坠机的生化人？
The droid that crashed with me.
我只能指给你看
I can point you in the right direction.
不能陪你去 我和别人有约
I can't join you. I have a previous engagement.
掉下来了 葛立 不要乱弄
This looks off. Golic, don't fidget.
怎么会这样？
What's all this shit?
根本没有包好
It's not properly wrapped.
- 他笨头笨脑 - 只会吃
- What the hell's he ever do right? - Eat. He does that pretty good.
葛立 你为墨菲点枝蜡烛
Golic. You light a candle for Murphy.
我会点很多支
I'll light a thousand.
他真好 从未抱怨过
He was special. Never complained about me once.
我喜欢他
I loved him.
真的是那样吗？
Is it true what they say?
他的头被打碎了？
His head split into 100 pieces?
谁有火柴？
OK, who's got the matches?
- 克先生 请坐 - 谢谢
- Sit down, Mr. Clemens. - Thank you.
- 加糖？ - 不用
- Sugar? - No, thanks.
- 加奶？ - 一点点
- Milk? - Just a little, please.
谢谢 亚伦先生
Thank you, Mr. Aaron.
给我听好 你这浑蛋 你再耍我 我就斩开你两半
Listen to me, you piece of shit! Screw with me one more time, I'll cut you in half.
对不起 我听不懂
I'm sorry, I don't think I understand.
七点我接到总公司的消息
At 0700 hours I received word from the network.
据我所知 那是这儿…
This is the first high-level communication
收到的第一份高阶层讯息
this installation has ever received, to my knowledge.
他们要我们看牢这女人 她是最高优先考虑
They want this woman looked after. They consider her to be high priority.
- 为什么？ - 我也不知道
- Why? - I have no idea.
你为何让她离开医疗室？
Why did you let her out of the infirmary?
墨菲发生意外 是因为
This accident with Murphy is what happens
你让人满脑子歪念乱跑
when one of these dumb sons of bitches gets a hard-on.
我是医生 你是狱卒
I'm a doctor, you're the jailer.
我们都知道你的真面目
We both know exactly what you are.
坐下
Sit down!
我认为我最好离开 在你身边令我非常不愉快
I think it might be better if I left. I find you unpleasant to be around.
是吗？你要想想 克先生
Isn't that lovely! Consider this, Mr. Clemens.
你要我把你的臭史 告诉你的新朋友吗？
How would you like me to explain your sordid history to your new-found friend?
为了她个人的想法
For her personal edification, of course.
给我坐下来
Now sit the hell down.
我不喜欢你 你喜怒无常 傲慢无理 也可能很危险
I don't like you. You're unpredictable, insolent, possibly dangerous.
你对任何事都有疑问
You question everything.
如果这里不需要医疗主任 我马上要你滚蛋
If I didn't need a medical officer, I wouldn't let you within light years of this operation.
- 我感激不尽 - 少讲风凉话
- I'm eternally grateful. - Keep your sarcasms to yourself.
现在…我该知道什么事？
Now, is there anything I should know?
- 关于什么？ - 那女人 少骗我
- About what? - About the woman. Don't play with me.
你几乎随时在她旁边
You spend every second you can with her.
鬼才相信你是为了治疗
And I have my suspicions that not all of your concerns with her are medical.
她跟你说过什么？
Has she said anything to you?
她从哪里来？有什么任务？ 为什么会在逃生艇内？
About where she's from, what her mission is? What she was doing in an EEV?
她说她们打了败仗
She said she was part of a combat unit that came to grief.
我想其他都是机密
Beyond that, I assume it's all classified.
我没再给她压力
I haven't pressed her for more.
- 就这样？真的吗？ - 对
- That's all? - That's all.
- 你确定 - 是
- You sure? - Yes.
- 没有了 - 没有
- Nothing more? - No.
滚出去
Get out of here.
闭嘴 你这个婊子
Shut up, you fuckin' bitch!
闭嘴 婊子
Shut up, you bitch!
放开我
Let go of me!
- 去你的 - 不要动
- Fuck you! No! - Hold still!
不
No!
你没事吧？
You OK?
你这王八蛋
Son of a bitch!
快走 我得重新教育几位弟兄
Take off. I gotta re-educate some of the brothers.
谈一下心灵改革的问题
We've gotta discuss some matters of the spirit.
香烟
Cigarettes!
干吧
Let's do it.
这里有十条街这么长
This is like ten city blocks.
- 有多少？ - 这是第176个
- How many? - This makes 176.
吃东西小声点 我正在算这区段有多大
Can't you chew any quieter? I'm trying to figure how big this compartment is.
- 你这么吵我无法思考 - 别说脏话
- I can't think with this goddamn noise... - You're not supposed to swear.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们绕行过整个区段
We've encircled this entire compartment...
- 嘿！ - 干嘛？
- Hey! - What?
- 什么狗屁玩意？ - 说脏话
- What the shit is doing that? - Swearing!
闭嘴 说狗屁没关系 我又没骂上帝
Shut up! It's all right to say "shit". It ain't against God.
蜡烛怎么了？
What's going on with the candles?
一定是附近通风孔 吹来的逆风
Must be the wind from one of the vent shafts. Backwash from the closest circulating unit.
要是蜡烛都被吹熄 我们怎么知道位置？
If all the candles go out, how do we know where we are?
只好派人回去 重新点亮
Somebody will have to go back and relight them.
我去吧
I guess I'm nominated.
小心点 兄弟
Watch your step, brother.
好了 谁在开玩笑？
OK, who are the comedians?
没有
No!
快跑
Go!
快 抓住
Quick, in here!
救我 救我
Help me, help me!
走！快走！
Go! Fuckin' go!
走 走 快点
Go on! Go on! Quick!
拿来
Give me that.
把这臭东西弄掉
Get this fuckin' thing off me!
放开我
Let me go!
嘿
Hey.
- 蕾普莉 - 嗨 主教
- Hello, Ripley. - Hello, Bishop.
- 你感觉如何？ - 我的腿很痛
- How are you feeling? - My legs hurt.
- 我很难过 - 没关系 我只是个烤面包机
- I'm sorry. - That's OK. I'm just a glorified toaster.
你还好吗？ 我喜欢你的新发型
How are you? I like your new haircut.
- 你能查出航行记录器资料？ - 没问题
- Can you access data on the flight recorder? - No problem.
葛立
Golic?
好了
I'm home.
苏拉可号发生什么事？ 低温舱为何弹射出来？
What happened on the Sulaco? Why were our cryo-tubes ejected?
静态平衡受干扰
Stasis interrupted.
低温舱起火 重覆 低温舱…
Fire in cryogenic compartment. Repeat: Fire in cryogenic...
怎么回事？怎么起火的？
What happened? What started the fire, Bishop?
你听得到吗？
Can you hear me?
电线短路 地板的材料烧起来
The fire was electrical. It was in the subflooring.
救生船脱离母舰前 有没有东西在舰上？
Did the sensors pick up anything moving around prior to separation?
这儿好暗 蕾普莉 我的视力大不如前
It's very dark here. I'm not what I used to be.
告诉我 记录器有没有显示？
Just tell me. Does the recorder indicate anything?
舰上有没有异形？
Was there an alien on board?
有
Yes.
它还在苏拉可号 还是和我们一起坠机？
Is it on the Sulaco or did it come with us in the EEV?
它一直都和我们一起
It was with us all the way.
公司知不知道？
Does the company know?
公司知道舰上的每一件事
The company knows everything that happened on the ship.
一切都输入电脑 传回总公司
It all goes into the computer and gets sent back to network.
他们还是要异形
And they want it?
帮个忙 切断电源
I hurt. Do me a favor. Disconnect me.
就算我被修好 也无法回复正常
I could be reworked. But I'll never be top-of-the-line again.
我宁愿消失
I'd rather be nothing.
你肯定？
You sure?
就当为我好吧 蕾普莉
Do it for me, Ripley.
不是我 不是我干的
It wasn't me! I didn't do it!
是…是那一条龙
Help me. It was the dragon.
吸食人的心灵 谁也无法阻挡
Feeds on minds. Nobody can stop it.
- 伯格和雷恩呢？ - 全像猪一样被宰了
- What about Boggs and Rains? - Slaughtered like pigs.
不是我 不是我
It wasn't me. It wasn't me.
他完全疯了 早该用铁炼锁住
Stark raving mad. It wasn't anyone's fault, but he should have been chained up.
你说得对 长官 他发疯了
You called it, sir. Mad as a fuckin' hatter.
把他隔离 别引起恐慌
Keep him separated. Don't want him causing a panic.
- 克里蒙斯 - 是
- Clemens! - Yeah.
- 让这白痴安静下来 - 我们得先弄清楚弟兄的下落
- Sedate this poor idiot. - Not until we know about the brothers.
振作一点 告诉我
Now, pull yourself together. Talk to me now.
- 伯格和雷恩在哪里？ - 不是我
- Where are Boggs and Rains? - It wasn't me.
没有用 问不出来的
You're not gonna get anything out of him.
我们得派出搜索队
We'll have to send out a search team.
这畜牲可能杀了他们
There's a good chance this simple bastard has murdered them.
你还不知道
You don't know that.
他没骗过我
He's never lied to me.
他是个疯疯癫癫的傻子
He's crazy, he's a fool, but he's not a liar.
不过他不会说谎
He's telling the truth.
我想跟他谈谈这条龙
I'd like to talk to him about this... dragon.
- 那是一条龙 - 你别想跟任何人说话 中尉
- It's a dragon! - You're not talking to anyone.
我对你的意见没兴趣 你根本搞不清状况
I'm not interested in your opinion, because you are not in full possession of the facts.
他曾犯下多宗杀人案 是个残忍的凶手
He is a convicted murderer, known for particularly brutal crimes.
- 对不对 迪伦先生？ - 对…那是真的
- Isn't that right, Mr. Dillon? - Yeah. That part's right.
那我就和你谈 这很重要
Then I'll talk to you. It's important.
我完成职务后很乐意和你谈
When I have finished with my official duties, I'll be pleased to have a little chat. Yes?
让我弄清楚 中尉
Let me see if I have this correct, Lieutenant.
这生物有8尺高 血液是强酸 坐你的太空船到达此地
It's an eight-foot creature with acid for blood, and it arrived on your spaceship.
它见人就杀 性情不太友善
It kills on sight and is generally unpleasant.
你当然期望我信你的话
And you expect me to accept all this on your word.
不 我不期望任何事
No. I don't expect anything.
- 故事很精彩 亚伦先生 - 是的 很精彩
- Quite a story, Mr. Aaron. - Right, sir. It's a beauty.
- 我没听过这种故事 - 我想也没有
- Never heard anything quite like it, sir. - Expect not.
告诉我 你建议我们怎么做？
Tell me, Lieutenant, what would you suggest we do?
- 你们有什么武器？ - 这是监狱
- What kind of weapons have you got? - This is a prison.
- 不能让囚犯碰武器 - 以免他们杀了你？
- We don't allow prisoners access to firearms. - It keeps them from killing you.
是的 它根本逃不出去
Yeah. There's no way to escape.
下一班补给船到达时 公司会派人消灭它
With the arrival of the next supply ship, the company will eliminate it.
这是个最高设防的监狱
This is a maximum-security prison...
你们却没有任何武器？
and you have no weapons of any kind?
屠宰场有几把屠刀 饭堂也有 还有几把斧头
We have some carving knives in the abattoir, a few more in the mess hall, some fire axes.
- 没有太多厉害武器 - 只有这些？
- Nothing terribly formidable. - That's all?
我们推行荣誉制度
We're on the honor system.
- 我们完蛋了 - 不
- Then we're fucked. - No.
只有你完蛋了 我把你关在医疗室
You're fucked. Confined to the infirmary. Quarantined.
亚伦先生会护送你去
Mr. Aaron will escort you.
你在那儿最安全 对吗？
You'll be safe from any nasty beasts while you're there.
这才乖
Good girl.
全体到饭堂报到 狱长安德鲁要开会
Let's all report to the mess hall. The superintendent wants a meeting.
立刻到饭堂报到
Mess hall, right away, people.
能不能离开？有办法逃生？
Isn't there any way off of this place? Some way to escape?
补给船每六个月来一次
No. A supply ship comes every six months.
只有这样？
That's it?
可恶
Fuck.
很快就有人来接你
They are sending somebody to pick you up quite soon.
很快是多快？
Really? What's soon?
不知道 以前没有人急着来这里
I don't know. Nobody's ever been in a hurry to get here before.
跟我说 安德鲁和你谈些什么？
Do you want to tell me what you and Andrews talked about?
不
No.
你会说我疯了
You'd just say I'm crazy.
这么说有点不厚道
That's a bit uncharitable.
你感觉如何？
How are you feeling?
不太好
Not so hot.
喉咙痛 胃部不舒服
Sore throat, sick to my stomach.
- 而且气坏了 - 在这种情况下我能了解
- Pissed off. - Understandable, given the circumstances.
也许我 该给你打一剂特别的药
Perhaps I should give you one of my special cocktails.
为什么大家都互相指责？
I don't know why everybody blames everybody.
人非圣贤 我们只是凡人
Nobody's perfect. We're only human.
没有一个人是完美的
There's no such thing as a perfect human.
这里是疯狂世界
In an insane world,
正常人也要变成疯子
a sane man must appear insane.
讲得真好 葛立
That's very profound, Golic.
谢谢
Thank you.
你结婚了吗？
You married?
- 我？ - 你应该结婚生子
- Me? - You should get married, have kids.
你这么漂亮
Pretty girl.
我曾认识 很多漂亮女孩
I used to know lots of them. Back home.
她们很喜欢我
They used to like me.
过一阵子就变心
For a while.
你也会死的
You're gonna die, too.
你有没有？
Are you?
- 什么？ - 结婚
- What? - Married.
- 干嘛？ - 只是好奇
- Why? - Just curious.
没有
No.
- 你也坦白点 如何？ - 讲清楚一点
- How about leveling with me? - Could you be more specific?
你没说你为何被派来这里
When I asked how you got assigned here, you avoided the question.
我提到你脑后的监狱识别条码 你又顾左右而言他
Then when I asked about the prison ID tattooed on your head, you ducked me again.
说来话长 令人伤心 而且通俗煽情
It's a long, sad story. And more than a little melodramatic.
说来听听
Try me.
既然你这么想听
If you insist.
我毕业以后
After my student years,
虽然我已经对吗啡上瘾
despite the fact that I had become secretly addicted to morphine,
我仍被认为 是最有前途的医生
I was considered to be most promising. A man with a future.
我当专科实习医生 在急诊室当值36小时
During my first residency I did a 36-hour stretch on an ER.
我跑出去 喝得酩酊大醉
So I went out and I got more than a little drunk.
然后我又被召回
Then I got called back.
一座炼油厂的蒸汽炉爆炸 30名伤者
Boiler had blown in a fuel plant and there were 30 casualties.
11人死亡
And 11 of them died.
不是因为意外 而是因为我开错止痛药剂量
Not as a result of the accident, but because I prescribed the wrong dosage of painkiller.
我服刑七年 执照被降为3C
I got seven years in prison and my license reduced to a three-C.
- 至少我戒掉吗啡瘾 - 很遗憾
- At least I got off the morphine. - I'm sorry.
我的惩罚还算轻
I think I was let off lightly.
你在这里服刑？
Did you serve your time here?
我和这群乌合之众混熟了
I got to know this motley crew quite well.
他们留下来 我也留下了
So when they stayed, I stayed.
没有人愿意聘用我
Nobody else would employ me.
你还愿意让我打针吗？
So, do you still trust me with a needle?
很好
Magnificent.
主呀 给我们力量来坚守
Give us strength, O Lord, to endure
我们只是上帝手中 卑微的罪人
We recognize that we are poor sinners in the hands of an angry god
请以手包围我们 守护我们
Let the circle be unbroken until the day.
- 阿们 - 阿们
Amen.
这里出了什么事？
What the fuck is happening here?
出了这么一大堆事情
What the fuck is this bullshit that's coming down.
有人死了 有人要强暴 弟兄出了麻烦
We got a murder, we got a rape, we got brothers in trouble.
不要再闹事了
I don't want no more bullshit around here!
出了问题 我们要团结
Now, we got problems, we stand together.
是的 谢谢 迪伦先生
Yes. Thank you, Mr. Dillon.
再一次 这是谣言管制会议
All right. Once again this is Rumor Control.
以下是案情
Here are the facts.
早上八点 囚犯墨菲因为粗心
At 0800 hours, prisoner Murphy, through carelessness on his part,
在第17通风孔死去
was found dead in vent shaft 17.
他似乎被吸入通风扇门
He seems to have been sucked into a ventilator fan.
晚上九点 囚犯葛立出现 精神错乱
At about 2100 hours, prisoner Golic reappeared in a deranged state.
囚犯伯格和雷恩失踪
Prisoners Boggs and Rains are missing.
很可能是遇害
There seems to be a good chance that they have met with foul play
遭囚犯葛立杀害
at the hands of prisoner Golic.
我们必须组组一支搜索队
We need to organize and send out a search party.
有人自愿我们会很感激
Volunteers will be appreciated.
这座监狱一直相安无事
I think it's fair to say that our smoothly running facility
突然出现一些问题
has suddenly developed a few problems.
希望大家 能在这几天提起精神
I can only hope we are able to all pull together over the next few days,
直到救援小组 接走蕾普莉中尉
until the rescue team arrives for Lt Ripley.
- 它来了 它杀死克里蒙斯 - 马上停止这种谣言
- It's here! It got Clemens! - Stop this raving at once.
我跟你说它来了
I'm telling you! It's here!
亚伦 把那笨女人带回医疗室
Aaron, get that foolish woman back to the infirmary.
- 那是什么？ - 快跑
- What is that? - Move it!
可恶
Fuck!
主呀 我们感谢你
We give you thanks, O Lord.
您的愤怒已显现 我们知道审判快到
The wrath has come, the time is near for us to be judged.
世界末日将要降临
The Apocalypse is upon us.
让我们有所准备
Let us be ready.
得到您的饶恕
Let your mercy be just.
- 好可怕 - 阿们
- It was massive. - Amen!
- 我在那里 我看到了 - 我知道
- I was there. I saw it. - Yeah, I know.
现在该怎么办？ 谁来指挥？
What the fuck do we do now? Who's in fucking charge?
我们得组组起来 对吧？
Organize! We gotta organize, right?
对 我有指挥权
Right! I'm next in line.
- 让85指挥？完了 - 别那么叫我
- 85's gonna be in charge. Give us a break! - Don't call me that!
我不可能取代安德鲁 他是好人
There's no way I can replace Andrews. He was a good man.
- 虽然你们不喜欢他 - 亚伦 我们不想听屁话
- I know you didn't appreciate him... - Aaron, we don't wanna hear that shit now.
妹子 你呢？你是个军官 展露一点领导才能吧
Sister, what about you? You an officer. How about showing us a little leadership?
别管她 你来指挥
Forget fuckin' Shirley Temple! You take charge.
- 对 - 反正这里都是你在管
- Right. - You run things here anyway.
不可能 我没当官的材料
No fuckin' way. I'm not the officer type.
我只会管我自己
I just take care of my own.
这臭怪物想要什么？
Well, what does this fuckin' beast want?
这老妈到底指不指挥？
Is this mother gonna try for us all?
要
Yeah.
这下可好 你想怎么阻止它？
Ain't that sweet! How are we gonna stop it?
- 我们没有武器 对吧？ - 对
- You have no weapons. Is that correct? - Right.
我看到的和这只不一样
I haven't seen one exactly like this before.
它的动作有点不同
It moves differently.
其他那些什么都不怕 只怕火
But the others were afraid of fire. Not much else.
- 能不能封锁这地方？ - 没办法 共有六百个通气管
- Can we seal off this area? - No chance. There's 600 air ducts...
录影设备呢？ 这里到处都有闭路电视系统
Video? There's closed-circuit monitors everywhere. We could use that.
闭路电视系统多年没用 这里什么都不能用
The video system hasn't worked in years. Nothing much works here.
很多科技用品 都没办法修好
We've got technology, no way to fix it.
- 85想说的是… - 别那么叫我
- 85 is trying to tell you... - Don't call me that!
没有娱乐中心 气候控制 没有视讯系统
We ain't got no entertainment center. No climate control, no video system.
没有监视 没有电雪柜 没有雪糕
No surveillance. No freezers. No fuckin' ice cream.
没有避孕套 没有女人
No rubbers, no women.
没有枪 什么都没有
No guns. All we got here is shit!
跟她谈有个屁用？ 她把那臭东西带来
What the hell are we even talking to her for? She brought the fucker.
何不砍下她的头 塞进墙壁？
Why don't we just get her head and shove it through the fuckin' wall?
这样最好
Sounds good to me.
莫斯
Morse.
好了
Right. Right.
我们该怎么办？
What are we going to do?
这是什么？
What's this?
那条通道从饭堂通往医疗室 是个通风孔
That leads from the mess hall to the infirmary. It's a ventilation shaft.
我们从那里进去 把它逼出来
Then we go in there. Flush it out.
那里的隧道有好几里长
Hey, look, there's miles and miles of tunnel through there.
它走不了太远
It won't go far.
它会在这里筑巢
It'll nest in this area.
就在…这附近
Right around... here.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
它就像只狮子 紧跟着斑马群
It's like a lion. It sticks close to the zebras.
斑马？别开玩笑
Zebras? Oh, right.
这么暗跑来跑去？ 走出主通风孔就没有电灯
But running around here in the dark? Outside of this main shaft there's no overheads.
- 不是有手电筒吗？ - 有几千个 没有电池
- Don't we have flashlights? - Thousands of them, but no batteries.
火把呢？我们能生火吧？
Torches? Do we have the capacity to make fire?
人类从石器时代起 就有这能力
Most humans have enjoyed that privilege since the Stone Age.
你用不着讽刺我
No need to be sarcastic.
这里没用过 这里打算放核废料
Never been used. They were gonna dump nuclear crap in there.
一直没空 里头空无一物
Never did. It's clean as a whistle inside.
这里是出入的唯一通道？
This is the only way in or out?
没错 墙壁有6尺多厚 实心钢造的
That's right. Walls are six feet thick. Solid steel.
他们知道怎么保护这些婴儿
They knew how to build these babies.
任何东西被关进去 绝对出不来
You're saying we get something in there, there's no way it can get out?
对 无路可逃
That's right. No fucking way.
我们放在这里 忘了叫什么
It's kept here. Forget what it's called.
- 圭乃特利西特林 - 我知道
- Quinitricetyline. - I knew that.
我把工作分配好 让迪伦髹油
I've gotta get these section arrangements organized with Dillon for the paint brush, uh...
- 现在… - 大卫
- So, um... - David...
- 你把这些油桶整理好 - 知道了 85
- You can get these drums organized. - Right, 85.
还有…别那么叫我
And, uh... don't call me that.
85到底是什么意思？
What's this "85" thing?
我们偷看过他的档案 那是他的智商
A couple of us sneaked a look at his personnel file. It's his IQ.
我看过这种油桶 掉在海滩木屋
I saw a drum of this stuff fall into a beachhead bunker once.
爆炸令码头三个半月 没有鱼群
The blast put a tug in dry dock for 17 weeks.
厉害的玩意
Great stuff!
让我搞清楚
All right, let me get this straight.
你想用火把它烧出通风管
You wanna burn it down and out of the pipes,
逼进这里 把门锁上 然后把它困住？
force it in here, slam the door, and trap its ass?
对
Right.
你要我们 这些天生罪犯帮忙？
And you want help from us Y-chromo boys, huh?
你有别的事要做吗？
You got something better to do?
我们为何要替你 冒险拼命？
Why should we put our ass on the line for you?
你们早就有危险
Your ass is already on the line.
问题是你打算怎么办？
The only question is what are you gonna do about it?
你看 两千个电池 只有一个用得着
Look at this. There's only one of these batteries in 2,000 that works.
还未算最糟
Hey, it could have been a lot worse.
可能照不亮
We might have got the paintbrush detail.
这玩意真臭
Man, this stuff stinks!
真是臭死了
This shit smells awful.
- 真的要臭死人了 - 应该要戴氧气筒
- I can't believe the fucking fumes. - You need a fuckin' pipe for breathing.
不要深呼吸
Don't breathe too hard.
你想念医生 对吧？
You miss Doc, right?
你怎么这么说？
What makes you say that?
你们两个很亲密
I thought you two got real close.
我猜你很爱偷窥
I guess you've been looking through some keyholes.
我是那么想的
That's what I thought.
- 你还好吗？ - 还好
- Are you OK? - Yeah, I'm fine.
真的吗？ 可是你看起来不太好
Whatever you say, but you don't look OK to me, sister.
我很好
I'm fine.
我讨厌这地方
I hate this place. I hate this place.
除了我们 绝对还有别的东西
There's definitely something in here with us.
我没打信号别点火 这是信号
Don't light the fire until I give the signal. This is the signal.
懂吗？记得住吗？
Got it? Can you remember that?
糟糕
Shit!
不 不
No! No!
怎么不等信号？
Wait for the fucking signal!
趴下
Get down!
快点 我们得找出洒水器 快救他们
Come on! We gotta find the sprinklers. We gotta help these guys.
快点 跑呀
Come on. Move! Move!
到废料处理场 别开门
Get to the waste dump. Don't open the door!
不会有事的
You're all right. You're gonna be all right.
火熄了
The fire's out.
朱德
Jude. Jude!
去把洒水器打开
Get to the sprinklers and turn 'em on.
快带他出去
We gotta get him outta here.
我们带你出去
We're getting you out.
它在你后面
Jude! Behind you!
开门
Open the door!
快点
Come on! Come on!
来捉我呀
Come and get me, fucker!
虽然他们受难
Even for those who have fallen,
我们仍应欣慰
this is a time of rejoicing.
向他们的勇气致敬
We salute their courage.
他们会永垂不朽
They will live forever.
死亡并不代表真正死去
Those that are dead are not dead.
他们升上天去
They have moved up.
到了更高的境界
They have moved to a higher place.
疯子
Crazy bastards.
克里蒙斯常叫做迪伦圣兵
Clemens used to call them Dillon's God Squad.
令他们幸免于难
It keeps 'em out of mischief.
- 你不信宗教？ - 我？
- You're not the religious type? - Me?
才不 我要工作
Shit, no. I got a job.
我想救援队四五天就会到了
Look. I figure the rescue team gets here in four, five days.
顶多是六天
Six, tops.
他们一来 拿出机关枪
They open the door, go in there with smart guns,
轰死它
and kill it.
有消息吗？
What have you heard from them?
没有 只说收到讯息
Nothing much. We got a "Message received".
后来又说 你是最高优先考虑
Later we got something that said you were top priority.
什么也不说 因为我们在边疆
They don't cut us in on much. We're the arse end of the totem pole here.
要是他们不想杀怪物呢？
What if they don't want to kill it?
- 带回去吗？ - 是
- Take it back? - Yeah.
他们疯了 一定要杀了它
They're not lunatics. They gotta kill it.
对吗？
Right?
莫斯 把我放开
Morse, please cut me loose.
- 不可以 - 很痛
- No fucking way. - Come on. It hurts.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 我没做什么 - 不要和我说话
- I haven't done nothing. - Just don't talk to me.
- 拜托 我做了什么？ - 告诉你我要怎么做
- Please! What did I do? - I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我要看管着你 那是我的事
Sit here and guard your arse, like I'm supposed to.
我不想惹怒迪伦
I don't need any fuckin' trouble with Dillon.
我只告诉他 那条龙杀了伯格和雷恩
All I did was tell him about the dragon, what it did to Boggs and Rains.
我没说谎 你看到了
I didn't lie. You saw it.
可恶 我看到了
Fuckin' A, I saw it.
拜托 它一进来 我就死了 我跑不了
Come on, please! If this gets in here, I'm dead. I can't run.
它不会来的 它会被困住
It's not gonna get in here. We got it trapped.
那也不会怎样 快点
So what's the big deal? Come on.
- 我每次都先给你烟 - 是
- Don't I always give you cigarettes first? - Yeah.
我不是你朋友吗？
Aren't I your friend?
我爱你 莫斯
I love you, Morse.
有何不可？
Why not?
乖一点 不准惹事 别害我
You better behave yourself. No fucking around or I'll get nothing but shit.
怪物在哪里？
So where've they got it?
在废置炉 把它困住
In a waste tank. We got that sucker nailed.
我想再看看怪物
Gotta see it again.
你说什么鬼话？
What the fuck you talkin' about?
不给你香烟了
No more cigarettes for you.
第一步完成了 要说什么？
We got the first part. Now what do we say?
告诉他们是我们捉的
Tell them we trapped it.
- 那叫什么？ - 异形怪物
- What do we call it? - A xenomorph.
对
Right.
怎么拼音？
How do you spell it?
捉到异形怪物
请批准消灭
- 杀不了的 又没有武器 - 对
- We can't kill it. We don't have any weapons. - Right.
费欧娜161 C级监狱
通讯卫星通报
维兰德-宇塔尼 收到报告
看吧 就是这样 当我们狗屁
See? That's all they ever tell us. They treat us like shit.
救援队将在12时抵达
不允许消灭异形怪物
重复:救援队到达前避免接触
要求不批准
- 时好时坏 - 你在说什么？
- Off and on. - What the hell you talking about?
说话呀
Talk to me, the beast!
不可以进去
You can't go in there.
那怪物会吃掉你的
The big motherfucker will eat you alive.
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉 抱歉 抱歉 抱歉
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry!
告诉我要怎么做
Tell me what to do next.
他们要来带走怪物
So they're coming to take this thing away.
他们会这么做 根本就不杀死
Yeah, they're gonna try. They don't wanna kill it.
我们得想办法
We gotta figure out a way to do it.
为什么我们要杀它？ 反正公司会来解决
Why do we have to kill it? You just said the company's coming for it.
对 他们是来带走怪物 用作研究武器
That's right. They wanna take it back, as some sort of weapon.
- 有何不可？ - 他们不知道它的危险性
- What's wrong with that? - They don't understand it'll kill them all.
我说了 有何不可？
Like I said, what's wrong with that?
没有 但很多无辜的人会死
Nothing's wrong with that, except a lot of innocent people will die.
- 我以为你有宗教信仰 - 你不明白
- I thought you were a religious man. - You don't understand.
外面的世界 对我们已经不存在
That world out there doesn't exist for us any more.
我们有自己的世界
We got our own little world down here.
虽然不大 却是我们的
It ain't much, but it's ours.
别人都可以死吗？
So fuck everybody else?
不 所有人都可以
No. Fuck them.
- 迪伦 - 是
- Hey, Dillon? - Yeah.
迪伦
Dillon.
有个小问题
We got a teeny-weeny problem.
这下好了
Fuckin' great!
那疯小子放走怪物 自作自受
The miserable, crazy son of a bitch let it loose. Got what he fuckin' deserved.
现在怎么办？
Now what are we gonna do?
安德鲁是对的 应该把那小子锁住的
Andrews was right. Should have kept the shithead chained up.
- 你还好吗？ - 去她的 那怪物还在外面
- You OK? - Piss on her. The fuckin' thing's loose.
- 该怎么办？ - 我说过了
- What are we gonna do? - I just said that.
你这小王八蛋让葛立逃跑
You're the dumb prick that let Golic out. You miserable little shit!
- 好了 住嘴 - 叫那个小丑识相点
- Cut that shit out. - Tell your fuckin' bozo to shape up.
- 你觉得呢？ - 到逃生艇
- What do you think? - I think I have to get to the EEV.
- 为什么？ - 我们得用神经扫描器
- Why? What's up? - I just have to use the neuroscanner.
- 你看来很憔悴 - 管她好不好 现在怎么办？
- You don't look so good. - Who gives a shit! What are we gonna do?
你想挨揍吗 笨蛋？ 闭上你的臭嘴 别让大家惊慌
Do you want a smack in the mouth, you stupid wanker? Stop causing panic!
惊慌？ 你笨得连惊慌也不会写
Panic? You're so stupid, you couldn't spell it. Don't talk to me about panic!
你们两个闭嘴
Shut up, both of you!
闭嘴
Shut up!
- 我们都没有办法了 - 不出奇
- Well, I'm out of ideas. - Surprise me.
- 外面怎么样？ - 太厉害了
- What about outside? - Great idea!
两天后日出 现在零下40度
Sun doesn't come up for two days, it's 40 below zero. That makes a lot of sense!
是呀 让那怪物把我们当午餐
So you just want us to stay here and let this thing have us for lunch.
叫所有仍生还的人集合 到大厅聚集
Get everybody that's still left together. Get 'em into the assembly hall.
好
OK.
她上哪里去了？
Where'd she go?
需要帮忙吗？
Need any help?
我不是故意吓你 你不应该一个人乱走
I didn't mean to scare you. You shouldn't be wandering around alone.
帮我个忙 替我按键盘
Do me a favor and run this keyboard, will you?
好
OK.
- 我该怎么做？ - 按B或C C是什么？
- What do I do? - Hit B or C. What's C?
- 显示生命机能 - 就是那个
- "Display bio-functions"? - That's it.
行了 现在呢？
OK, we're hot. Now what?
让它转一圈
Let it run its cycle.
- 很模糊 - 按放大键
- It's real fuzzy. - Hit enhancement.
继续看
Keep looking.
- 我看不懂这玩意儿 - 如果出血就有暗色块
- I don't know how to read this stuff. - Hemorrhaging will show as a dark patch.
在头骨根部找细微裂痕
Look for hairline fractures through the base of the skull.
小小的白线
Little white lines.
异 体 组 织
怎么了？
What is it?
你体内也有一只
I think you've got one inside of you.
不可能
That's not possible.
异 体 组 织
什么样子？
What does it look like?
DNA资料扫描中
组织类型不明
- 太可怕了 - 我得看看它
- Horrible. - I have to see it.
- 定格 - 你最好别看
- Freeze it! - You don't want to look at it.
我很难过
I'm sorry.
那怪物还在 它逃出来了
All right, the fuckin' thing is loose. It's out there.
救援队带着武器 快到达了
A rescue team is on its way with guns and shit.
现在危机四伏
Right now, there isn't any place that's real safe.
大家在这里集合
We stay here in the assembly hall.
这里他妈的没有空调
This place never had any fuckin' air conditioning.
如果怪物来了 一定走大门
If it comes in, it'll be through these doors.
要有人守门 怪物来了才知道
We'll post a guard who'll let us know if it's coming.
现在先躲好 准备好迎接它
In the meantime, you lay low, be ready and stay right,
万一你的大限来临
in case your time comes.
迪伦 少鬼话连篇 我们都会被困死在这里的
Don't you start bullshitting, Dillon. We're gonna be trapped in here like rats.
有武器小刀的 拿出来用吧
You got a weapon. You got a blade. You take it out and you fuckin' use it!
对 用小刀就能杀死怪物
Oh, right. So you think we're gonna stab this motherfucker to death.
杀死个鬼
I don't think shit!
只能在被杀死前令它受伤
Maybe you'll hurt it before it takes you out, huh?
那是个主意 谁有更好的主意？
Isn't that something? Any of you got any better ideas?
告诉你们 等救援队到达前我们已经死光
And I'll tell you. Until the rescue team gets here, we're fucked!
大家先作准备吧
So you better get prepared.
我才不留在这里
Well, I ain't stayin' here.
随便你
Then suit yourself.
点火
Fire.
- 是熔炉 - 对 快过去看
- The furnace. - Yeah. Let's make it to the furnace.
老天哪
Holy shit.
- 这下好了 - 真他妈的
- Well, all right. - Fuckin' A.
真他妈的 说得对
Too fuckin' right, it's right.
设定好了 你想说什么？
It's up. What do you want to say?
跟他们说这里充满毒气
Tell them the whole place has gone toxic.
别开玩笑 救援小组会折返
Are you kidding? The rescue team will turn back.
- 我知道 - 你在胡说什么？
- Yeah, I know. - What are you talking about?
我们得靠他们杀死怪物
Our only hope is that they kill this fucker.
他们也许能想办法 把你冷藏起来动手术
Maybe they can do something for you. I don't know, freeze you, do an operation.
要是异形逃走 就会杀光所有人
If this organism gets off the planet, it'll kill everything.
公司根本不在乎
The company doesn't care about that.
他们只想拿它 来研究生化武器
They just want it for their bio-weapons division, OK?
我们不能让他们来
So we can't let them come here.
管你的
Fuck you!
我很遗憾你体内有那东西 可是他们得救我
I'm sorry you've got this thing inside you, but I'm getting rescued.
我才不管那些囚犯 我有老婆、孩子
I don't care about these prisoners, but I've got a wife and a kid.
- 下次轮到我回家 - 我知道
- I go home on the next rotation. - I know. This is hard.
不过我要传送这讯息 我要密码
But I'm gonna send this message and I need that fucking code.
抱歉 这是机密
I'm sorry, Ripley. It's classified.
你这笨蛋一定要这么做
You stupid little shit, this has got to be done!
别无选择
OK? There are no alternatives!
我不会给你密码 不可能
You're not getting it! No fucking way!
听着 我跟你无冤无仇
Look, it's nothing personal.
我认为你会没有事
Understand? I think you're OK.
谢了
Thanks.
你有什么主意吗？
Have you got any ideas?
它不会杀我
It won't kill me.
我孕育新女王
I'm carrying the new queen.
它不会杀死自己的未来
It won't kill its future.
那怪物有这么聪明？
You really wanna bet this thing's that smart?
或许我去找它
Maybe I'll go find it.
看它到底有多聪明
See how smart it is.
- 你要去找它？ - 对
- You're gonna go and look for it? - Yeah.
我知道它在哪里
I have a pretty good idea of where it is.
它就在下面 地下室
It's just down there, in the basement.
这整个地方都是地下室
This whole place is a basement.
我只是打个比喻
It's a metaphor.
你来不来？
Wanna come?
该死
Fuck me!
收到逃生艇扫描资料
紧急医疗小组 将在2小时内到达
最高优先考虑
隔离蕾普莉中尉
等   待   确   认
要找你时你在哪里呢？
Where are you when I need you?
别怕
Don't be afraid.
我是你的家人
I'm part of the family.
你进入我的生命这么久 我已经不记得其他事情
You've been in my life so long, I can't remember anything else.
现在帮我个忙吧
Now do something for me.
很简单
It's easy.
只要…
Just...
只要发挥你的本能
Just do what you do.
- 它不肯杀我 - 你应该躲起来
- It won't kill me. - You're supposed to be laying low.
我体内也有一只
I have one inside of me.
大只的怪物不肯杀我
The big one won't kill its own.
- 你在说什么？ - 我刚刚看到了
- What are you talking about? - I just saw it, an hour ago.
我就站在它旁边
I stood right next to it.
它可以杀我 可是它不杀我
I could have been lunch, but it wouldn't touch me.
它跑掉了
It ran away.
- 它知道我在孕育它的后代 - 胡说
- It knows I'm carrying its future. - Bullshit.
- 你怎么知道你体内也有？ - 我透过断层扫描看到它
- How do you know the thing's inside you? - I saw it, on the CAT scan.
它是个女王 会产卵
It's a queen. An egg-layer.
它会生出上千个这种怪物
It can make thousands more.
听起来还是胡说八道
It still sounds like bullshit to me.
那东西是怎么进入你体内？
If that thing's inside you, how did it get there?
我在长眠的时候吧
When I was in hypersleep, I guess.
它攻击我
I was violated.
现在我成为女王之母
And now I get to be the mother of the leader.
我的时间不多
I don't have much time.
无法做我该做的事
And I can't do what I should.
我要你帮忙
I need you to help me.
你得杀死我
I need you to kill me.
- 你在胡说什么？ - 反正我死定了
- What the fuck are you talking about? - I'm dead anyway.
我活不了
I can't survive it.
我体内的异形 会繁殖上千只后代
But the one inside of me can generate thousands more.
可以杀光整个宇宙
It can wipe out the whole universe.
它一定得死
It has to die.
必须有人杀死我
So somebody's gotta kill me.
你办得到吗？
Are you up to it?
这点你不必担心
You don't have to worry about that.
不必致词
No speeches.
也不必祷告
No prayers.
- 怎么回事？ - 我不喜欢服输
- What's going on? - I don't like losing a fight.
对任何人或物都一样
Not to nobody, not to nothing.
那东西杀死半数的弟兄 另一半也被吓得半死
That thing has already killed half my men and got the other half scared shitless.
只要它还活着 你就别想拯救宇宙
As long as it's alive, sister, you're not gonna save any universe.
- 你是胆小鬼 - 我要捉住它
- You fuckin' coward! - I want that thing!
我要你帮我逮住它
I wanna get this thing and I need you to do it.
它不肯杀你 也许对我们有利
And if it won't kill you, then maybe that helps us fight it.
不然就少说废话
Otherwise, fuck you!
你不帮忙就去死
Go kill yourself.
迪伦
Dillon!
干掉这怪物之后 你就得除掉我
We waste this thing, then you take care of me.
没问题
No problem.
你会死得痛快 不受折磨
Quick, easy and painless.
由你自己决定
This is the choice.
你们想坐以待毙 还是奋战到死
You die sitting here on your ass, or you die out there.
至少我们该试试 让它好看
At least we take a shot. We owe it one!
它把我们都害惨了
It's fucked us up.
应该来个以牙还牙 要怎么做？
Maybe we can get even for the others. Now, how do you want it?
- 你在胡说什么？ - 我是说去杀了那混帐东西
- What the fuck are you talking about? - Killing that big motherfucker.
等一下 救援队要来了 我们只要等就好了
Hold it, hold it. The rescue team's on its way. We could just sit this out.
- 要救援谁呢？ - 我们呀
- The rescue team for who? - For us.
- 他们只想要怪物 - 我才不管他们要什么
- They just want the beast. You know that. - I don't give a damn what they want.
- 他们不会逐个接走吧 - 这我不敢说
- They're not gonna pick us off one by one. - I wouldn't be so sure.
- 他们是来带我们回家的 - 不是我们
- Come on! They'll take us home. - They're not gonna take "us" home.
我们不必跟它拼命
Still doesn't mean we should fight it.
你们都是笨蛋 我有老婆孩子
I've got a wife and a kid...
没有人睬你 85 你只是个臭员工
You're a fuckin' company man!
好吧 我是员工 不是臭囚犯
Yeah, OK. I'm a company man, I'm not a fuckin' criminal.
你一直骂我笨 起码我够聪明 不像你们永远被关在这里
You tell me how dumb I am. I'm smart enough not to have a life sentence on this rock!
- 去你的头 - 滚开 85！
- Shut your face! - Piss off, 85!
我够聪明 我会等武器来了再上战场
And I'm smart enough to wait for some firepower to show up before we fight it!
好吧 你就乖乖坐在这儿
OK, just sit here on your asses. Fine.
- 我也要乖乖坐在这里儿 - 没问题
- How about if I sit here on my ass? - No problem.
我忘了
Oh, I forgot.
你向上帝祈求获得永生
You're the guy that's made a deal with God to live forever, huh?
其余的胆小鬼 也可以坐着不动
And all the rest of you pussies can sit it out, too.
我和她会负责打仗
Me and her'll do all the fighting.
好吧 不过我要杀死它 我恨透那东西
OK. Look, I want the same thing as you. I want to see it dead. I hate the fucker!
它也杀死我的好朋友
It killed my mates, too!
为何不等到公司 把枪运来再动手？
Why the fuck can't we wait for the company and have some guns on our side?
- 为何一定要白白送死？ - 对
- Why should we go on a fucking suicide run? - Right!
因为公司不会杀死它 他们可能杀了你们灭口
Because they won't kill it. They might kill you for having seen it, but they won't kill it.
太荒谬了 胡说八道 他们不会杀我们
That is crazy! That is horseshit! They will not kill us.
当他们第一次听到有异形 就说可以牺牲船员
When they first heard about this thing, it was "crew expendable".
上次派去的海军陆战队 也一样可以牺牲
The next time, they sent in marines. They were expendable, too.
难道他们会在乎
What makes you think they'll care about a bunch of lifers
关在外太空的囚犯吗？
who found God at the ass-end of space?
难道他们会让你们 破坏他们的计划吗？
You really think they're gonna let you interfere with their plans for this thing?
他们认为我们是垃圾
They think we're crud.
根本就不在乎你们的死活
And they don't give a fuck about one friend of yours that's... that's died.
没有人在乎
Not one.
- 你有计划吗？ - 这是个铸铅厂 不是吗？
- Have you got some sort of plan? - This is a lead works, isn't it?
只要把异形丢进模子 让它溺死在滚烫的铅里
All we gotta do is lure the fuckin' beast into the mold. Drown it in hot lead.
好吧 我们该怎么做？
Oh, right. So how do we do that?
没错 谁来当饵？
Yeah. What are we gonna use for bait?
该死
Aw, fuck!
你们迟早都得死
We're all gonna die.
问题是怎样死法
The only question is when.
这地方很适合 做上天堂的第一步
This is as good a place as any to take our first steps to heaven.
问题只是要如何上去
The only question is how you check out.
你们要死得轰轰烈烈
Do you want it on your feet
还是跪地求饶呢？
or on your fucking knees, begging?
我不会求饶
I ain't much for begging.
也没有人饶过我
Nobody ever gave me nothing.
我说干掉那怪物 跟他拼命
So I say fuck that thing! Let's fight it!
- 好吧 我们跟它拼了
- Fuck it. Let's go, boys! - OK.
它冲过来怎么办？
What the fuck are we gonna do if it runs at us?
最好先想出好办法来
Better have some fucking good ideas.
一号门开启
Door 1 open.
你们几时用过这地方？
When was the last time you used this place?
五、六年前用过
We fired it up five, six years ago.
- 你确定活塞还能用？ - 没有一样东西能确定
- You sure the piston's gonna work? - There's nothing for sure in this place.
它被困进去你就拉下把手
We trap it here first, then you pull the lever.
关起活塞 把它推下模子 然后把铅倒进去
The piston's gonna push it into the mold. One of the guys will pour the lead.
- 很简单 它死定了 - 要是有人搞砸呢？
- End of his ass, end of story. - What if somebody screws it up?
那就完蛋了 我们只有一次机会
We're fucked. You got one chance, one shot at it.
没时间重新再来 记住 当你拉下把手
We'll never have time to reset it. Now, remember, you pull the lever,
你也会和那怪物 困在里面一会儿
for a few seconds you're gonna be trapped in here with that thing.
你们不出差错 我也不会
You guys don't drop the ball, I won't.
它最好真的不肯杀你
You better be right about that thing not wanting you.
它想逃出去只有一条路 通过凹槽 通过你
Because if it wants out, that's how it's gonna go: Through that alcove, through you.
- 你在那里？ - 我在附近
- Where will you be? - Around.
- 其他人呢？ - 在祷告
Where are the others?
你相信有天堂吗？
Do you believe in this heaven shit?
不知道
I don't know.
可恶
Fuck it.
还有什么能相信呢？
What else have we got to believe in?
那就是事实
Ain't that the fuckin' truth.
去它的
What the fuck.
对不？
Right?
我听不到…
I can't hear...
动作要迅速
Let's blitz this thing!
七号门关闭
Closing door 7.
情况不妙
I don't know about this shit.
各位
Hey, guys!
我的门坏了
My door ain't working.
- 他在说什么？ - 我们最好重新考虑
- What the fuck's he saying? - I think we better rethink this thing!
有人听到声音吗？
Did anybody hear anything?
来抓我呀 王八蛋
Come on! Come and get me, you fucker.
它在后面
It's behind me!
开始了
It's started.
- 在后面 - 它在B通道
- It's still behind me! - It's in channel B.
在后面 快关门
It's still behind me. Shut the doors!
它一定朝A通道去了
Must be heading over to channel A.
这怪物真的发怒了
This thing is really pissed off!
- 你刚刚说B吗？ - 不 E
- Did you say B? - No, E.
- 你叫我留在这里 - 动作快点
- You said we should stay here! - Move your ass!
莫斯
Morse?
凯文
Kevin!
找到文生了
I think I've found Vincent!
丑八怪 来抓我呀 快来呀
Hey, fuckface, come and get me!
用力一点
Take your best shot!
你抓不到我
You can't get me!
A7关闭
A7 closed!
它在东厢 B7关闭
Over in the east wing. Door B7 safe!
你也在这儿？ 大家都到E通道
You too? OK, over to E, everybody!
- 在哪里？ - 这里
- Where the fuck is E? - This way.
好 快追
Right. Track!
怎样过来？
How did I get here?
他们去哪里？怎么不照计划？
Where the hell are they going? What about the plan?
- 你免疫了 他们可没有 - 那该怎么办？
- You're immune! They're not! - So what are we doing?
- 随机应变 - 正在随机应变
- Improvising. - We're improvising.
这下好了
Great.
过来 猫咪 过来
Here! Here, kitty, kitty.
过来 猫咪
Here, kitty, kitty.
我的天
Oh, my God...
你这畜牲
You bastard!
它过来了
It's coming!
从隧道过来 它盯上我们了
It's coming down through the tunnel! It's after us!
照计划把门关上
Shut the fucking doors!
天哪 在上面 迪伦
Jeez, it's on the fucking ceiling! Dillon!
来人呀 这不是演习
Anybody! This is not a drill!
凯文 葛瑞戈 你们在哪里？
Kevin! Gregor! Where the fuck are you?
凯文
Kevin!
我们又回到A通道
Now I'm back in A!
第3道门 F通道已关闭
Door three, F channel, closed.
希望是
I hope.
你在干什么？别那样拿 这样拿
What the fuck are you doing? Don't hold it like that, hold it like this.
你会刺死人 蠢蛋
You'll kill someone, you fuckin' moron!
莫斯 凯文
Morse! Kevin!
葛瑞戈
Gregor!
他们只要跑过通道就行
All they have to do is run down a damn corridor.
留在这里
Stay here.
它到底在哪里？
Where the hell is it?
来了 老天
It's coming. Oh, Jesus.
在那里
There!
不要打开活塞
No! Don't start the piston!
我们得先困住它
No! We have to trap it!
你在干嘛？它跑掉了
What are you doing? It's gone! No!
它跑掉了 好吗？
It's gone! OK?
好
OK.
凯文
Kevin!
不要挣扎 别动 不要挣扎
Don't move! Don't struggle!
来呀 来呀
Come on. Come on, Kevin. Come on!
- 关门 - 它来了
- The doors. - It's coming!
准备活塞
Take the piston!
好了 没事了
It's all right.
没事了 凯文
It's OK. It's all right, Kevin.
凯文 凯文
Kevin. Kevin!
把他放下 他死了 引它进来
Leave him! He's dead. Lure it in.
- 可恶 还要多久？ - 四、五分钟
- Shit! How much time? - I'm not sure. Four or five minutes.
我们得在活塞封闭之前 把它引回这里
We got to get it back in here before the piston seals this place off. Now let's move it!
救命
Help me!
朱德
Jude!
迪伦 救命
Dillon! Help me!
它在追我
It's coming at me!
别往后看 赶快跑
Don't look back, Jude! Run as fast as you fuckin' can!
迪伦 救我 拜托
Dillon, help me! Please!
谢天谢地 你们终于来了
Jesus Christ! Thank God you're here.
狱吏亚伦 长官 137512 幸存的人不多
Warder Aaron, sir. 137512. Not many of us left, sir.
蕾普莉中尉呢？ 她还活着吗？
Where is Lt Ripley? Is she still alive?
她还活着 就在熔炉那里
If she's alive, she's in the furnace.
她和怪物在铸铅厂
She's in the lead works with the beast.
她不肯等你们
Wouldn't wait.
- 老天 - 你这浑蛋把我吓得半死
- Jesus Christ. - You fucker. Scared me shitless!
我以为你是那怪物 大笨蛋
I thought you were the fuckin' beast. You fucker!
笨蛋
Wanker!
来呀 你这畜牲
Move. Come on, you bastard!
来呀 来呀
Come on! Get out of there!
过来
Come here!
蕾普莉 时间无多
Ripley, we're running out of time!
蕾普莉 你在哪里？
Ripley, where are you?
不
No!
上面 我在上面
Dillon, over here!
迪伦
Dillon!
来呀 过来
Come on. Get out of there!
你在干嘛？ 你有病吗？放过它
What the fuck is wrong with you?! Let it go!
- 好 成功了 到活塞 - 快尖叫 让它跟来
- Yes, it's working! To the piston! - Scream. Let it follow us.
- 快点 - 把它引到活塞前
- Come on! - We gotta get it in front of the piston!
- 跟上来了 - 过来 你这怪物
- It's following us! - Come on. Come and get us!
- 过来 - 到门边
- Come on! - Up to the door!
来呀 来呀
Come on! Come on, motherfucker!
快点 把门关上
Come on! Get the door!
- 把门关上
- Get the door! - Morse!
- 快关门 - 莫斯 把门关上
- Now! - Shut it! Shut it, Morse!
莫斯 把门关上
Morse! Shut the door!
- 快点 - 把门关上
- Now! - Shut the fuckin' door!
我去倒热铅
I'm going for the lead!
- 现在 - 你呢？
- Now! - What about you?
- 我要留下 - 这里会灌进十顿热铅
- I'm staying. - There'll be ten tons of hot lead in here.
- 我说过 我想死 - 我们说好了
- I'm telling you, I wanna die! - We got a deal.
记得吗？ 它先死 然后才是你
Remember? It dies first, then you!
你不走我也不走 快走吧
I'm not gonna move without you. Now get going!
- 迪伦 - 我在这儿挡住它
- Dillon? - I've gotta hold it here.
- 那我呢？ - 上帝会照顾你 妹子
- What about me? - God will take care of you, sister.
不
No!
把热铅倒下来
Pour the lead.
去你的
Now, fuck you.
- 不 - 快倒 蕾普莉 快呀
- No! - Go on, Ripley. Go on!
把铅倒下来 快点
Pour the lead, Ripley. Pour it now!
你只有这点能耐？来呀 浑蛋
Come on! Is that all you got? Fight, motherfucker!
- 快点 倒呀 - 莫斯 这里
- Come on, do it! - Morse, over here!
- 蕾普莉 - 把铅倒下去
- Ripley! - Pour the lead!
把铅倒下去
Pour the lead!
倒下去
Pour it!
最讨厌虫子了
I hate bugs!
蕾普莉 它热得滚烫
Ripley! It's burning hot.
打开洒水器
Hit the sprinkler!
淋死这王八蛋
Douse the fucker!
干掉你了
Gotcha!
好极了！
Yes!
- 不要再过来 - 等等 他们是来帮忙
- Don't come any closer. - Wait! They're here to help.
别过来
Stay where you are.
- 蕾普利 - 主教
- Ripley. - Bishop.
- 我是来帮助你的 - 别再骗我了
- I'm here to help you. - No more bullshit.
它在我体内蠕动
I just felt it move.
- 你知道我是谁吗？ - 你是个生化人
- You know who I am? - You're a droid.
与主教同型号 公司派来的
Same model as Bishop. Sent by the fucking company.
我不是主教那种生化人
No. I'm not the Bishop android.
他是我设计的
I designed it.
我是人类 公司派个熟悉面孔来找你
I'm very human. The company sent me here to show you a friendly face.
表示你有多重要
To demonstrate how important you are to us.
对我也是
To me.
- 你只想把它带回去 - 我们要杀了它 带你回家
- You wanna take it back. - We want to kill it and take you home.
才怪
Bullshit.
你错了 我们想帮你
You're wrong. We want to help.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
- 我们会替你取出它 - 然后留它活口
- We're gonna take that out of you. - And keep it.
我们不能让它活着 否则人类将面临危机
We can't let it live. Everything would be in jeopardy.
- 你不想把它带回去？ - 蕾普莉 时间不多
- You don't want to take it back? - Ripley, time is important.
我们要赶快解决这个恶魔
Let us deal with the malignancy.
救援舰有手术台 跟我来吧
We've got a surgical bay set up on the rescue ship. Come with me.
手术快速无痛
It's very quick. Painless.
只要几刀 两小时就好了
A couple of incisions. You'll be out for two hours.
一切就结束了
And then it's over.
你还能过正常生活
You still can have a life.
生儿育女
Children.
最重要的 你会知道它真正死了
And most important, you'll know it's dead.
让我帮你吧
Let me help you.
我怎样肯定
What guarantee do I have,
你们把它取出来
once you've taken it out,
就会消灭它？
that you'll destroy it?
你得相信我
You have to trust me.
求你相信我
Please? Trust me.
不
No.
这样有什么用？
What's this gonna achieve?
住手
Stop!
老天
Oh, Jesus!
莫斯
Morse.
- 你愿意帮助我吗？ - 你要我做什么？
- Will you help me? - What do you want me to do?
这是个误会 你们不该伤人
It was a mistake. There was no need for any of it.
可恶的生化人
Fuckin' android!
我不是生化人
I'm not a droid!
蕾普莉
Ripley!
想想能从它身上学到的
Think of all we could learn from it.
这是毕生难逢的机会
It's the chance of a lifetime!
你得让我留下它 它是个优秀生物
You must let me have it. It's a magnificent specimen.
不要拍摄
No pictures!
你疯了
You're crazy.
你要做什么？
What are you doing?
不
No!
- 快点 快点走 - 去你的
- Come on, you. Get going! - Fuck you!
…艾许和达拉斯船长 都死了
...Ash and Captain Dallas are dead.
货物和船全部被毁
Cargo and ship destroyed.
我在六周后将抵达边界
I should reach the frontier in about six weeks.
幸运的话 有人会来拯救
With a bit of luck, the network will pick me up.
我是蕾普莉 诺斯都罗莫号唯一生还者
This is Ripley, last survivor of the Nostromo,
报告完毕
signing off.
维兰德-宇塔尼公司
复仇 161星球
劳动监狱关闭封锁
监管驻防事务终止
存留铸炼设备
当废铁出售
传 讯 完 毕
原始字幕合成及特效：铭瑄@CMCT
1080p字幕特效：pengxu01767